From Taiwan to Shanghai, governments aren’t yelling “Ban gas bikes now!” —
They’re whispering sweetly:
“We’ll slowly persuade you to let go of that dear old scooter…”
…with cash, perks, and just enough infrastructure
so you won’t complain too loudly.
In Taiwan, electric bikes are seduced with VIP license plates,
special parking spots, discounts, and subsidies.
In Shanghai, officials took a firmer approach:
no more license plates for gas bikes, no renewals,
and mandatory “retirement” after 13 years
or 120,000 km — whichever comes first.
And it’s not just about banning —
they’ll even buy back your old ride.
Hand you a free metro pass,
build battery-swap stations for delivery riders,
and roll out metro lines faster
than you can say “pollution.”
At first, citizens were confused:
“How do we live without our scooters?”
But a few years later, they’re sipping bubble tea,
charging their e-bikes,
and reminiscing about their gas-powered days
like it’s ancient history.
You can’t kill off gas bikes overnight.
It takes finesse:
A little fear, a little funding,
some penalties, and a lot of public charm.
Every policy stick works better when it’s sugar-coated —
so the old bikes roll away,
and the people smile while waving goodbye.