When Physics is no longer… just formulas.
Hello, everyone.
If I told you… this year’s Physics exam would surprise you,
would you believe me?
Because in 2025, Physics has changed.
It has learned… to tell stories.
A story about an iron core lying still in a magnetic field.
A story about a light bulb that shines… not because of Ohm’s law,
but because of belief.
For the first time… the exam doesn’t just ask how many formulas you can remember.
It asks:
How much do you truly understand?
Can you follow a phenomenon,
analyze the clues,
and explain it… like a scientist?
But there’s more.
Physics doesn’t stand alone.
It shakes hands with Chemistry,
nods to Biology,
and smiles at Math… and Technology.
You have to connect.
You have to see the bigger picture.
You have to solve a question… that you’d never answer
if you treated each subject in isolation.
This is no longer Physics on paper.
This… is Physics in real life.
You don’t have to be Einstein.
You just need enough curiosity to ask:
“What’s really going on here?”
And enough patience to trace…
the current of your own thinking.
Because this exam…
doesn’t just test your memory.
It tests how you think.
How you connect ideas.
How you ask questions.
Because in the 21st century…
what matters is not how many formulas you know.
What matters… is whether you can look at a phenomenon,
hear a story… and decode it.