Tsunamis — just the name sounds like a drama queen with a grudge.
Somehow, humans — the only species smart enough to build beachfront villas — act totally shocked when the ocean decides to crash the party.
We build our dream homes “with an ocean view,” then scream bloody murder when the ocean takes a peek inside.
Nature isn’t evil — it just really hates being ignored.
Scientists say, “Don’t reclaim land from the sea.” Developers say, “But what about the oceanfront resort?”
So one sunny day, the tsunami rolls in — no invitation, no warning (well, technically there was), just a casual, “Sorry folks, I was here before you had deeds.”
To be fair, tsunamis are polite in their own way.
They come with alarms, flashing alerts, and scrolling red warnings.
But instead of running, people whip out their phones: “OMG guys look! The water’s rising!”
And the next thing you know, their video is part of a rescue team briefing.
Let’s be real: the tsunami isn’t the villain.
It’s just doing its job — reminding us that nature is not some theme park.
So if you’re still dreaming of building that 5-star hotel right on the edge of the surf… at least know how to swim.
Don’t mess with Mother Nature. When she claps back, it’s not gonna be cute.