Vietnam is in a tropical climate zone, so the weather is usually hot and rainy.
In the North, there are four seasons: spring, summer, fall and winter.
The summer is very hot, while the winter can be quite cold.
Occasionally, it even snows on the mountains, like in the Hoang Lien Son range or in Sapa.
In the Autumn, the leaves turn into yellow or red.
Dead leaves fall along the streets, in neighborhoods and in parks.
Autumn in the North is truly beautiful.
It often inspires poets and artists.
In the spring, flowers bloom everywhere.
In Northern Vietnam, spring is the season of festivals and a time for beautiful girls and handsome boys go out to dates.
In South Vietnam, there are only two seasons: the dry season and the wet season.
The dry season begins in late November and ends in early May.
On the other hand, the wet season begins in early May and lasts until the end of November.
In the South, it usually rains in the afternoon or evening.
Unlike the North, there are rarely storms in the South.
The climate in Southern Vietnam is mild and not severe,
that is why Southern people are often seen as friendly and easygoing (sociable).