Happiness is just the state of mind, and it usually links with health.
Almost everyone thinks that only rich people have happiness.
Because they have a lot of money, but poor people do not.
But that is not right, because many rich people are not happy in their life.
Maybe they have no peace in their heart or not enough health to enjoy life.
If a poor person becomes a little rich, he wishes he would be richer.
His wish is never limited.
A billionaire never thinks that his health is enough.
I think the idea of a happy life is that we should be satisfied with what we have.
If we have a sufficient income, let's be content with it.
Vice versa, if we want to be richer and richer, we will come to the end of zero.
They say that: Your happiness will naturally disappear
if you keep looking for another greater happiness.
I hope: There is no need for both of you to try to find it.
It is always around you.