Jurassic World: Rebirth brings a fresh twist to the franchise, with Scarlett Johansson playing Zora Bennett — a scientist recruited for a groundbreaking genetic project involving dinosaurs and medical innovation.
Set in a world where dinosaurs coexist with humans, a biotech company engineers the D-Rex, a creature with regenerative powers meant for healing — until things inevitably go wrong.
The film’s greatest strength lies in its visuals.
The dinosaurs, especially the mutated D-Rex, are impressively lifelike.
Action scenes across jungles, cities, and the creature’s lair are stunning and full of scale.
Unfortunately, the script doesn’t match the visuals.
Though the film hints at big ideas — like bioethics and genetic responsibility — these are explored only superficially.
The plot rushes from action to action, offering little character development.
Zora’s internal conflict as a scientist is barely addressed.
The pacing is solid but lacks emotional highs or memorable twists, leaving the film visually engaging but emotionally flat.
Despite its flaws, Rebirth delivers as a popcorn blockbuster — fun for fans of dinosaur thrills, but not for those seeking depth or innovation.
Review Summary
Strengths: Spectacular visuals, realistic dinosaurs, strong action, Johansson’s screen presence
Weaknesses: Weak script, shallow themes, limited emotional impact
Rating: 6.8/10 – Eye-catching and entertaining, but lacking narrative depth.