Jurassic World: Rebirth brings a fresh twist to the franchise.
Scarlett Johansson plays Zora Bennett — a scientist on a genetic project.
She’s recruited for research involving dinosaurs and medical innovation.
In a world where dinosaurs coexist with humans, chaos begins.
A biotech firm creates the D-Rex, designed to heal — but it backfires.
The film’s greatest strength lies in its visuals.
The dinosaurs, especially the mutated D-Rex, are impressively lifelike.
Action scenes in jungles, cities, and lairs are stunning and epic.
Unfortunately, the script doesn’t match the visual quality.
Themes like bioethics and genetic responsibility are barely explored.
The story jumps between action scenes with minimal character development.
Zora’s internal struggle as a scientist is barely addressed.
The pacing is steady but lacks emotional highs or twists.
It’s visually engaging but emotionally flat.
Still, Rebirth succeeds as a popcorn blockbuster.
It’s fun for fans of dinosaur thrills and big effects.
But it doesn’t offer depth or innovation.
Review Summary — Strengths: visuals, dinosaurs, action, Johansson.
Weaknesses: weak script, shallow themes, low emotional impact.
Rating: 6.8/10 – Eye-catching and entertaining, but lacking depth.