Dolphins are not fish, but rather warm-blooded mammals.
They live in groups and communicate with each other using their own language.
In this respect, they are similar to other animals, such as birds and bees.
Dolphins are very different from land-dwelling mammals.
Their brains are about the same size as ours.
They live fairly long lives—at least 20 to 30 years.
Strangely, dolphins seem to like humans.
There are thousands of stories about friendships between dolphins and people.
Some dolphins often seek out humans.
They leave their groups and enter our harbors, swimming back and forth near beaches.
They like playing with people.
Nowadays, some countries still hunt dolphins for food.
But many nations around the world are now protecting them.
In these countries, killing dolphins is against the law.
In Vietnam, people greatly respect dolphins.
They see dolphins as sacred animals.
Vietnamese fishermen never dare to harm dolphins or whales.
They believe dolphins and whales bring them good luck.