Saigon is a big city in Vietnam.
It is located in southern Vietnam and has a population of about 10 million people.
There are two major rivers in Saigon: the Saigon River and the Nha Be River.
If there is no traffic jam, it takes about 3 hours to get to Saigon from Ba To by coach.
After arriving at Suoi Tien Park, you can take a bus to Ben Thanh Market.
The ticket costs 10,000 VND. Children under 6 years old can travel for free.
Before visiting District 1, you should wear sport shoes instead of high heels,
and carry light luggage because you will need to walk a lot.
Saigon has many places to visit.
First, we go to Ben Thanh Market, which is over 100 years old.
You shouldn’t buy too many things because you might not have enough strength to keep walking afterward.
Leaving Ben Thanh Market, we will visit the walking street — Bui Vien Street.
If you enter by bicycle or motorbike, you may be fined from 200,000 VND to 300,000 VND.
After the walking street, we will visit Bach Dang Harbor and Nha Rong Wharf.
Then, we visit the zoo, which has many animals from around the world.
After the zoo, we stop by Turtle Lake to relax and have a drink.
To continue, we visit the War Remnants Museum,
where you can learn about the brutality of war.
After leaving, everyone prays: “No more war in the world.”
I dare say, at this point, you probably just want to find a restaurant
to recover after a tiring day of walking.
If you have a lot of money, I’ll take you to visit Can Tho —
the capital of the Western Region. Please!