Good morning, everyone.
Today, I want to take you on a journey — not just to a place,
but into the heart of one of Vietnam’s most dynamic and unforgettable cities: Saigon.
Saigon, or Ho Chi Minh City as it’s officially known, is not just big — it’s alive.
Home to over 10 million people, it pulses with energy, ambition, and stories at every corner.
With two rivers — the Saigon River and the Nha Be River — flowing through it,
this city has long been a crossroads of cultures, ideas, and dreams.
From my small hometown of Ba To, it takes about three hours by coach to reach Saigon —
assuming the traffic is kind, which, as you might imagine, it often isn’t.
But the moment you arrive, everything changes.
Let’s begin at Suoi Tien Theme Park,
a place where Vietnamese legends and modern amusement blend into something magical.
From there, hop on a bus, and soon you’ll find yourself at the iconic Ben Thanh Market,
a 100-year-old cultural treasure.
It’s a place where the smells of street food dance with the sound of bargaining voices —
and yes, where your legs might give out before your curiosity does.
A piece of advice: when exploring District 1, skip the high heels.
Wear your most comfortable shoes, because Saigon invites you to walk — and walk you will.
After Ben Thanh, we make our way to Bui Vien Walking Street, where the city never sleeps.
But beware — if you try to enter on a bicycle or motorbike,
the fine could be up to 300,000 VND.
Rules aside, this street is a celebration of youth, music, and freedom.
Then, we move to the quieter waters of Bach Dang Harbor and Nha Rong Wharf,
where history whispers in the wind.
You begin to feel that Saigon isn’t just modern — it remembers.
We visit the Zoo, where animals from around the world
remind us of the beauty of biodiversity.
We stop at Turtle Lake, not for sightseeing,
but to sit, sip a drink, and let the city slow down for just a moment.
But the most powerful stop on our journey is the War Remnants Museum.
It’s not easy to walk through. It’s painful, eye-opening, and deeply human.
And when you walk out, there’s only one thing left to say:
“No more war in the world.”
By the end of the day, your feet will hurt, your head will be spinning, and your heart will be full.
And in that moment, you’ll probably look at me and say, “Can we eat now?”
And I’ll smile and say,
“If you’ve still got the energy — and a bit of cash —
how about we continue our adventure to Can Tho, the capital of Vietnam’s Western Region?”
Because that’s the thing about Saigon — once you start exploring, it’s hard to stop.
Thank you.