Those who work hard every day with their hands don’t need to exercise — for example, ploughmen, blacksmiths, coolies, or bricklayers.
What they want after a hard-working day is to come home and relax.
Those who work with their brains, like students, secretaries, or businessmen, have to exercise because they don’t get much physical activity in their jobs.
Exercising is very important for our health.
If we don’t use our muscles, they will weaken, our bodies will become obese, and many diseases will affect us.
We have many choices for exercising.
We can play sports like tennis, ping pong, badminton, or football.
Girls can do lighter activities like dancing, yoga, or aerobics.
Jogging is the cheapest sport. It is suitable for everyone.
We can jog in the early morning or late afternoon.
People say, “A sound mind is always in a strong and energetic body.”
Do you want to prolong or shorten your life?
Do you want the road to the graveyard from your house to be farther or nearer?
That depends on your choice.