Vietnamese people usually have three meals a day — breakfast, lunch, and dinner.
Actors, actresses, singers and people who work at night often eat breakfast pretty late, around 10 AM.
It is called a brunch — a mix between a late breakfast and an early lunch.
They often eat late night snacks, sometimes around 11 PM.
Vietnamese people are different from Europeans and Americans. We don’t eat a lot of fatty foods.
Our diet is pretty healthy. We eat a lot of vegetables, fruits, fish and very little meat.
Poor families usually have breakfast at home while wealthier people often eat out at cafes or restaurants.
Doctors say that breakfast is really important — it’s the main source of energy for the whole day.
Nowadays, Vietnamese people often have a light lunch.
Factory workers and government employees usually eat in the cafeteria or at restaurants because they don’t have time to go home for lunch.
Vietnamese families usually have dinner around 6 or 7 PM.
It’s considered family time — a chance for everyone to be together.
Young women often skip dinner at 7 or 8 PM because they’re afraid of gaining weight.
They say, “It’s easier to gain weight than to stay slim.”
Meanwhile, some poor people don’t even have enough food to eat — they suffer from malnutrition.
We should drink enough water every day — at least 2 liters.
We shouldn’t drink sugary sodas because they’re bad for our health.