Vietnamese people love football.
Not just weekend-kickaround love,
but the kind of love that makes you skip school, skip work —
sometimes skip paychecks — just to catch a match.
Every time the national team plays, it feels like a nationwide holiday.
Red flags, speakers blaring, pots and pans banging down every alley.
But behind the patriotic glow of this football fever
lies a shady sideline… drenched in betting slips.
While mouths shout “Vietnam champions!”,
fingers are quietly texting “over or under?”
The ball’s only been rolling for 10 minutes,
but for some, heart rates have spiked like the betting odds.
Some are so “passionate” they sell their bikes,
pawn their land deeds, go deep into debt —
all for a striker’s lucky foot.
That uncle at the café, talking like a FIFA analyst?
He’s actually praying for a goal to recover his losses.
And the neighbor lady?
She doesn’t even like football, but turns on the TV because
“if my husband wins, we eat pho;
if he loses, it’s instant noodles for a week.”
Sport is meant to build spirit, health, and national pride.
But for many, it’s become training ground for dodging debt,
chasing odds, and arguing with bookies.
Loving football is beautiful.
But if it costs you your house, your friendships, and your sanity,
that’s not passion — that’s organized delusion.