Hawkers usually walk around selling fruits, food, clothes, and all kinds of other stuff.
Some of them push carts from place to other place, while others ride bikes or motorbikes to carry their goods around.
Honestly, sometimes we hesitate to go to market or a shop outside just because we’re too busy.
But if hawkers bring their goods right to our doorstep, we’re more likely to buy — it saves time.
Plus, we still have the choice: to buy or not to buy.
That said, some hawkers do sell fake goods or spoiled food, and that’s really dangerous.
Unsanitary food can cause food poisoning or serious illnesses like typhoid or dysentery.
However, most hawkers are poor folks trying to make a living.
They have to work hard every day.
They don’t have stable jobs, but they’re trying to prove that they’re not useless — not just freeloaders.
Let’s be honest, we all want good jobs.
But those are not easy to come by, especially when we prefer playing to studying!
So remember this:
In the end, everything has its value!