The Whale God – Once a Sea Deity, Now a Floating Trash Can?
Back in the day, whales were sacred beings who saved fishermen at sea.
Now? They might need saving themselves.
Fishermen once worshiped them as ocean guardians — today’s youth worship the views and chase viral content.
Vietnam’s waters are still blue — but mostly the blue of plastic bags.
Whales still surface — but it’s their stomachs that float, bloated from swallowing size-42 sandals.
We call their beaching “resting” out of respect.
Yet the way we dump trash into the sea is making them “rest” for real.
And now, every time a whale appears, it’s like a red carpet event for the content vultures:
drones buzzing overhead, cameras zoomed in straight into the poor whale’s mouth mid-meal.
The small fish it was about to eat? Gone — scared off by the sound of livestream notifications.
The whale opens its mouth for a bite, but instead ends up in the news with a caption like:
“Emotional moment as whale returns to Vietnamese waters.”
Meanwhile, reporters storm the beach to interview… the waves,
asking locals how they “felt witnessing such a spiritual event” —
while the whale just wants to eat in peace before it washes ashore from sheer anxiety.
Once a divine protector, now a victim of pollution — and TikTok.
In this modern-day mythology, the monster isn’t a dragon —
it’s the guy holding a smartphone on record.