Today, traveling in Vietnam is quite difficult, especially in big cities like Hanoi, Da Nang, Sai Gon.
The streets are often overcrowded and in a deteriorated state. Every day, traffic jams occur at intersections.
Students, workers, and employees have to get up early to go to school or work, but traffic jams are unavoidable.
Sometimes, traffic police cannot manage the traffic effectively.
To get around the city, we often spend much more time, especially during rush hours.
In the rainy season, most of the roads are flooded because the drainage and sewage systems are frequently blocked.
Another cause of traffic jams is that some people do not obey traffic laws.
To move around the city, we can take a bus, a taxi, a cyclo.
Taxis are expensive but fast and comfortable.
While sitting in a taxi, we can sing, surf internet for updating information, watch movies.
If we want to travel from a city to another one, we can take a coach.
Vietnam has a pan Vietnamese railway system that connects Hanoi – our capital – with Sai Gon, which is known as the “Pearl of the Far East” in southern Vietnam.
If we want to save time, we can travel by airplane.
Time is very precious, but unfortunately, many poor people cannot afford to fly anywhere. How sad it is.