Xuyen Moc is a large district located in the north eastern part of Ba Ria - Vung Tau Province.
The district consists of 12 communes and one town, with a population of 170,000.
Make a tour around Xuyen Moc offers a view of vast rice fields, forests, mountains, rivers, and luxurious coastal resorts.
Phuoc Buu Town features a large lake and a beautiful park.
In the early mornings or late afternoons, locals often visit the park to exercise, engage in sports, and enjoy the fresh air.
On New Year’s Eve, crowds gather here to watch the fireworks.
Xuyen Moc District holds significant potential in various areas, including its beaches, forests, rice fields, industrial crops, fruit trees, and, most notably, tourism.
During weekends or public holidays, tourists from all over flock to the beaches to relax, swim, and savor fresh seafood.
The people of Xuyen Moc are known for their friendliness and hospitality.
If you find yourself with some free time, we warmly invite you to visit!
We hope you have a wonderful holiday experience!