A wedding ceremony is one of the most important events in a couple’s life when they want to get married.
Brides and grooms usually hold their wedding ceremony at home or at a restaurant.
They invite relatives, family members and friends to witness and share the joy of this happy day.
Among those present at the party, some of them are truly happy: the bride, groom and their parents.
Others may appear cheerful, but in reality, they are quietly sad.
They are the guests, because their salaries are limited and they have to attend too many wedding ceremonies in the same month.
After the wedding ceremony, the bride and groom usually travel somewhere for their honeymoon.
Rich couples travel abroad or to some famous places.
Poor couples have to honeymoon at home, or sometimes don’t have one at all,
because they have to work hard to pay off wedding debt.
But sadly, only a few couples can keep their happiness until the end of life.
Most others have to say goodbye just a few years after the wedding ceremony.
That’s modern life!