September 2 isn’t just a day off —
it’s a day when an entire nation remembers a defining moment in history.
When President Ho Chi Minh declared Vietnam’s independence,
boldly announcing to the world…
…that we are a free and sovereign people
who will never be conquered.
We take pride in a nation that, though small in size,
defeated mighty empires through sheer determination.
From epic victories in war
to resilient growth in peace,
our ancestors left behind a legacy of greatness
written in blood, courage, and sacrifice.
But today’s youth aren’t here to simply enjoy the fruits of peace —
we’re here to carry the torch.
Inventing technologies,
winning global competitions,
building products proudly labeled “Made in Vietnam”...
Every achievement is a modern continuation
of that patriotic spirit.
This year’s national concept could be:
“Rooted in Pride – Rising to the Future”
Our ancestors wrote history with valor.
Now it’s our turn —
to write the future with innovation and courage.
So that Vietnam may forever stand tall
on the global stage.