Nowadays, the world population is 7.5 billion,
and people live all over the Earth.
They live on the icy lands of the poles
and in the tropical rainforests along the equator.
They have climbed high mountains,
walked on the sea bed,
and even left the Earth to visit the Moon.
Humans are the most numerous and powerful species on Earth.
Animals can do some things better than we can.
Dogs can smell and hear better than we can.
Cats can see in the dark.
Birds can fly thousands of miles
and return to the exact same place every year.
But we are different. No animal builds churches,
plays football, tells jokes, gets married,
has prisons, bands, or presidential elections,
or walks on the Moon.
There is one thing that sets us apart from animals:
we love to talk, talk, and talk.
We are master communicators.
We can communicate in many ways—
with our facial expressions, our hands, our bodies, and our voices.
Most importantly, we can record what we say
and write down what we think.
We can communicate through space and time.
We have a sense of the past and of the future—
not just the present.
We are the only species capable of changing the entire world.
We are the only species that can choose:
either to take care of the world or to destroy it.