Drones – Flying Cameras with No Conscience
Once upon a time, the sky belonged to birds and clouds.
Today? It’s the playground of drones — robotic birds that don’t sleep, don’t chirp,
and don’t care if you’re in your pajamas on the balcony.
At first, drones were a tech dream: wedding shoots on mountaintops, beach resorts, home deliveries.
But in just a few years, they’ve become sky paparazzi, reluctant couriers, and sometimes… anonymous spies.
Tech fans say drones represent “freedom in the air.”
In reality, they make you want to hang a “Private airspace” sign in your backyard.
You go on a picnic — a drone follows. You watch the sunrise — a drone livestreams it first.
And in the wrong hands, a drone becomes a way to “share moments” — without your consent.
In rural areas, drones spray pesticides.
In the city, they deliver bubble tea.
In war zones, they offer “condolences via GPS.”
Yes — from toys to photographers to airborne threats — drones do it all.
And who controls them? A 17-year-old on a rooftop? A government far away?
The sky seems peaceful — but only because you can’t hear a camera zooming in.
Drones are convenient. Too bad they don’t come with a conscience.