Energy and America – When Trucks Drink Gas Like Americans Drink Pepsi
America has long been a symbol of power, freedom… and electricity consumption as if there were a nuclear reactor in every household.
In a place where refrigerators are bigger than student apartments in Asia, and air conditioners run 24/7—even when it’s snowing outside—energy isn’t just a necessity; it’s a national identity.
Cars? No, no—not “cars”—but four-wheeled beasts as long as two king-sized beds.
In Europe, people drive to get to work.
In America, some people drive just to take out the trash at the end of the driveway.
Every time gas prices go up, Americans sigh, shake their heads…
then drive their F-150s to the pump and fill the tank anyway.
The sun? The wind? Renewable energy?
Sure, it all sounds great… in commercials.
In reality, most of the power still comes from coal, oil, and a quiet hope that the rest of the world hasn’t noticed yet.
And then there’s summer—also known as “blackout season”—
when everyone turns on the A/C at once and the power grid decides to take a vacation.
The problem isn’t that there’s not enough electricity.
The problem is that you can’t run the hot tub, the electric stove, the hair dryer, and livestream TikTok all at the same time if you’re living in Texas in mid-July.
America also loves to “export energy”—in the form of bombs and foreign policy.
If your country has oil, get ready.
If you don’t want to sell it cheap, get really ready.
Because energy isn’t just fuel—it’s a language of diplomacy.
And in this game of chess, the U.S. usually owns the board… and the spotlight.
But to be fair, America has invested heavily in green tech:
Electric cars like Tesla? Fantastic!
Wind farms? Yes—but they take seven years to build because… the birds protested.
Solar panels? Wonderful—except they were installed in Oregon, where the sun comes out for about two weeks a year.
Conclusion? America leads the world—both in developing energy solutions and in using them up before anyone else can.
Because in America, people don’t just dream the American Dream.
They leave the lights on all night to dream it in full high definition.