Phuoc Buu Town, October 11th, 2019
My dearest love,
How are you and your family? What are you doing these days?
Are you working today or staying at home?
I wonder… do you ever whisper my name to yourself—whether in joy or in sorrow?
As my family and I, we’re all doing fine. Mom, Dad, and my siblings often speak of you.
But deep inside, I still feel sad… because I miss you.
Vietnam’s traditional Lunar New Year is coming soon—only 25 days left!
Our Tet holiday is very different from the American New Year.
Like the Chinese, we celebrate the Lunar New Year.
This year, Tet falls on January 25th, 2020 (solar calendar), which is also the 1st day of the Year of the Rat.
I’ve never celebrated Tet in America, so I don’t know what your New Year is like.
But Tet in Vietnam is always joyful and full of warmth.
During Tet, family members from all over return to gather under the same roof. Everyone is busy.
My father decorates the house and garden. My mother makes bánh chưng.
A square sticky rice cake filled with mung beans and pork.
I go to the market to buy cakes, fruits, food, and vegetables. My siblings clean the house.
Each of us has our own task.
In the evening, my whole family gathers around the fire, watching over the pot of bánh chưng...
...while sharing stories from the past and present. The Tet atmosphere is so warm and cozy.
On New Year’s Eve, no one in my family sleeps. We sit together, watch the apricot blossoms blooming...
...waiting for that sacred moment to arrive, when the old year has just passed and the new year begins.
My beloved,
Everyone in my family is joyful and excited. They all seem so content.
But as for me, there’s still something missing. It causes me deep, quiet pain—but also intense longing.
Yes… it’s yourself.
How can I be truly happy without you? Loving you brings me so much happiness...
...because you’ve filled my life with joy. And yet, loving you also brings me immense sorrow…
...because I fear losing you.
I wish you could be here with me this Tet. The both of us would…
Oh dear, I feel breathless just imagining it.
I’d better stop here.
It’s already past midnight.
Please take good care of yourself, okay?
And send my warmest regards to your parents and siblings.
Lots of love
xxx
Your little sweetheart,
Anh Tuyet