In Saigon, there are thousands of foreign language centers and schools.
You can learn English, French, German, Japanese, Korean, or Chinese if you wish.
Most learners study foreign languages at night when they are free, as they have to work during the day to earn a living.
They hope that by speaking a foreign language well, they will have a better chance of finding a good job.
In the evenings, thousands of people flock to language centers.
It is said that you can truly understand a nation’s people when you can speak their language.
This is absolutely true.
However, learning a language is not easy.
At the beginning of a course, many people register, but by the end, many have dropped out because it is too difficult.
The most important thing is patience—nothing is impossible if you are determined.
Today, you may not be able to speak yet, but tomorrow, next week, or next month… surely you will.
Stay optimistic! I wish you success.
And remember: On the road to success, there are no footprints of the lazy ones.