These days, eating isn’t just about staying alive — it’s a declaration.
What you put on your plate can reveal your tribe:
Team Meat or Team Greens, Team Detox or Team “More Fish Sauce, Please.”
Some go vegetarian as a spiritual path. Some, because it’s trending.
Others simply because they posted “starting a greener life” on Facebook last night —
and now every meal comes with hashtags like #HealthyLife and #MeatFreeMonday…
…even if they just dreamed of being chased by fried chicken in the park.
On the other side, hardcore meat lovers treat salad like it’s contagious.
Their go-to line: “How can raw vegetables be enough?”
— said while biting into a juicy pork belly skewer, chased with a sugary soda.
But here’s the truth: Vegetables aren’t saints, and meat isn’t the devil.
A stir-fried plate of pesticide-loaded veggies cooked in cheap reused oil
isn’t exactly pure and holy.
Just as a factory-marinated frozen pork chop from last year
won’t lead you to nutritional salvation either.
On the other hand, a free-range chicken — fed natural grains,
allowed to run around in the sun —
— could be more nourishing than tofu deep-fried
in oil that’s seen better decades.
If it’s natural, it’s good — whether it grows on a branch or walks on legs.
The problem isn’t whether you eat meat or plants.
The real question is: do you even know what you’re eating?
Where did it come from? How was it grown or raised?
Because it’s laughable to debate the ethics of eating meat…
while chewing on a soy sausage made from seventeen different lab-born ingredients.
And just as absurd to brag about “meaty strength”
without knowing the difference between wild-caught fish and farm-raised ones swimming in antibiotics.
At the end of the day, your body doesn’t need a belief system — it needs real food.
Diversity. Balance.
Ingredients that come from soil or sea, not slogans.
So whether you’re vegan or carnivore, remember this:
There’s nothing more dangerous than blind faith in a plate
that looks “moral” but isn’t even healthy.