Provincial Mergers in Vietnam: Major Reform with Far-Reaching Impact
Vietnam has officially entered a new phase of administrative reform on an unprecedented scale:
Merging provinces and cities to streamline the state apparatus, enhance governance efficiency, and reduce public spending.
A Landmark Policy Decision
In June 2025, the National Assembly of Vietnam passed a landmark resolution.
To reduce the number of provincial-level administrative units from 63 to 34:
Comprising 28 provinces and 6 centrally governed cities.
This was the culmination of years of research, evaluation, and preparation.
The objective goes beyond simplifying structures—it aims to foster regional connectivity.
Enable large-scale socio-economic development,
And create competitive urban centers that can integrate regionally and globally.
Concrete Changes Across Regions
Many localities have undergone the merger process.
The new Tuyen Quang province now includes both Tuyen Quang and Ha Giang.
Lao Cai has been merged with Yen Bai.
Thai Nguyen has united with Bac Kan.
In the South, Can Tho City has expanded by merging with Hau Giang and Soc Trang.
Da Nang has integrated with Quang Nam to form a major hub in Central Vietnam.
Opportunities and Challenges Interwoven
While the reform is expected to bring significant breakthroughs,
Implementation has raised practical challenges.
Changes in administrative boundaries have caused confusion in accessing public services.
Personnel redundancy due to overlapping functions is a pressing concern.
So are cultural differences between merged provinces, and underdeveloped infrastructure.
All of these affect management and operational efficiency.
Finding a Path Forward
Experts suggest several essential measures to maximize reform benefits:
• Transparent communication to ensure public consensus;
• Clear personnel policies, including support for displaced officials;
• Strategic investment in transportation and digital infrastructure;
• Public consultation on naming and administrative centers to ensure inclusivity.
A Challenge – and an Opportunity
Provincial mergers are more than redrawing administrative maps—
They represent a deep restructuring of how the state functions.
If managed effectively, this reform could be a powerful catalyst for Vietnam’s transition.
Toward a more efficient, modern, and sustainable governance model.
Vietnam’s journey of administrative reform is ongoing—
And the provincial merger is one of its opening chapters.