I usually wake up at 5 a.m. I exercise for about 30 minutes.
After that, I take a shower and have breakfast.
I leave for work at 7 a.m.
As my workplace is quite far from home, I usually have lunch at a nearby restaurant.
I take a short nap at the office during lunchtime.
My workday ends at 5 p.m.
In the evening, I often watch TV or read books.
Sometimes, I go to the movies or attend a concert with my friends.
My mom and younger brother also enjoy watching TV and movies.
On evenings when we don’t watch TV, we usually chat in the living room.
We go to bed at 11 p.m.
On weekends, my whole family is free.
We usually go to the beach or go shopping at the supermarket.
I really love weekends because I can relax and forget about work.