Hello everyone! Did you sleep well last night?
Hang, is your leg feeling better? And Tuyen, is your stomach still hurting?
Now let’s check out and continue our trip to the Western Region.
The first place we’ll visit is Can Tho City. Do you all still have money?
If someone’s run out of cash, go ahead and sell your gold.
And if you don’t have any gold, don’t worry — I’ll lend you some money.
Can Tho is the capital of the Western Region, which is why it’s called Tay Do – the “Western Capital.”
First, we’ll visit Phung Hiep Floating Market. We’ll rent a small boat for about 1 million VND.
While sitting in the boat, you can watch a truly unique market — one that you’ll only find in Vietnam.
This market has everything from top-tier goods to bargain-basement items.
If you’re thirsty or hungry, vendors will row straight to you.
And if any of you gentlemen are thinking about “sleeping on the boat,” let me just say: there are long-legged beauties in traditional áo bà ba outfits, ready to serve you from A to Z.
After leaving Ninh Kieu ferry station, we’ll visit the fruit gardens — also for 1 million VND.
Before we go, don’t eat anything yet — there are all kinds of delicious fruits waiting for you to try, like duku, durian, mangosteen, longan and more.
If you want to see plaswai, head over to the “cầu tỏm” (yes, that’s really the name), where you’ll see them fighting over food like gladiators.
And if you want to eat those catfish, just wait a moment — the orchard owner will serve them to you right away.
But be warned: after eating that catfish, you might just throw up your whole family tree — or everything you’ve ever eaten!